For freedom. For family. For the planet.
War for the Planet of the Apes is a drama, science
fiction, war film directed by Matt Reeves.
Caesar and his apes are forced into a deadly conflict with
an army of humans led by a ruthless Colonel.
After the apes suffer unimaginable losses, Caesar wrestles with his darker
instincts and begins his own mythic quest to avenge his kind.
As the journey finally brings them face to face, Caesar and the Colonel are pitted against each other in an
epic battle that will determine the fate of both their species and the future of the planet.
Caesar, played by Andy Serkis.
The Colonel, played by Woody Harrelson.
Maurice, played by Karin Konoval.
Rocket, played by Terry Notary.
Bad Ape, played by Steve Zahn.
Nova, played by Amiah Miller.
War for the Planet of the Apes is a 2017 American science fiction action film
directed by Matt Reeves, who co-wrote it with Mark Bomback.
The sequel to Dawn of the Planet of the Apes (2014), it is the third installment in
the Planet of the Apes reboot film series and the ninth film overall.
It stars Andy Serkis as Caesar, alongside Woody Harrelson and Steve Zahn.
The film takes place in 2028, two years after the events of Dawn and follows the conflict between apes and
humans as it has escalated into full war, while Caesar sets out to avenge those he has lost.
Development for War for the Planet of the Apes began in January 2014, after 20th Century Fox viewed
Reeves's cut of its predecessor; his return was soon confirmed, along with Bomback's.
A conditional 2016 release date was announced in May 2015, which led to a closer
and faster pre-production relationship between writer and director.
The film bears similarities to Battle for the Planet of the Apes (1973), with emphasis on
the effect of psychosocial development and interaction of apes and humans.
Casting began in August 2015 and finished that October, with principal photography commencing soon thereafter and
concluding in March 2016, with filming locations including Lower Mainland and the Kananaskis Range.
War for the Planet of the Apes premiered on July 10, 2017, at the SVA Theatre in New York
City, and was theatrically released worldwide by 20th Century Fox on July 14.
A critical and commercial success, it grossed over $490 million, and received nominations for Best Visual Effects and
Best Special Visual Effects at the 90th Academy Awards and 71st British Academy Film Awards, respectively.
A standalone sequel, Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes, was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of suicide, civil war, escape, winter, mutation.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.